Guide to the EAD SAX Papers, 2009-2010 LUE 00042
Special Collections Research Center
Guide to the EAD SAX Papers
2009-2010
LUE 00042
Special Collections Research Center
40.0 Linear feet 102 archival boxes
Collection includes diaries.
102 archival boxes
Biographical Note
Dr. Paul Dix was born in 1868 in Darmstadt, Germany. The grandson of a chief forester, Schenck studied forestry at Tubingen University and entered the state forest service in Hessen in 1890.
In 1898, with Vanderbilt's permission, the Biltmore Forest School (BFS) opened.
Chronology
1868 Born, Darmstadt Germany
1886 - 1891 Studied forestry in Tubingen and Giessen Universities
Scope and Content
This collection provides a detailed look into the personal and professional life of Paul Dix, the founder of the first American school of forestry.
Collection Organization
The collection is divided into 2 series. The first of these is Diaries.
Restrictions to Access
This collection is open for research; access requires at least 24 hours advance notice.
Acquisitions Information
The Carl Alwin Schenck Papers was received in a number of accessions from 1959 - 1990.
Biltmore Forest School.; Schenck, Carl Alwin, 1868-1955; Biltmore Forest (N.C.); Diaries; Forest products industry--North Carolina
- Diaries, 1890 - 1954; MC 00035 Series 01; 6.0 Linear feet; 12 archival boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  The first series of the collection, the Diaries, records personal notes from Biltmore Estate
  - 1890 - 1895 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1895 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1895 - 1955; MC 00035 Series 02; 10.5 Linear feet; 21 archival boxes
  The Correspondence series includes all letters.
  - Professional
    - Biltmore Estate and Forest
      - 1895 - October, 1908 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - November 1, 1908 - November 15, 1908 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Forestry Colleagues
    - Brandis, Dietrich
      - 1895 - 1899 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - 1900 - 1907 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Fernow, Bernhard, 1896 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Olmstead, Frederick Law
      - 1907 - 1949 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - 1950 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - 1951 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - 1952 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - 1953 - 1954 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Pinchot, Gifford
      - 1895 - 1899 (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - 1900 - 1908 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Price, Overton (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Schlich, William (Box 14, Folder 12)